Guide to the Stanford Historical Photograph Collection
Stanford University. Libraries.
- General Photographs, Series 1
  - Student Academics--Classroom--Fol.1 (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Student Academics--Classroom--Fol.2 (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Student Academics--Computers (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Student Academics--Fraternities (Box 43, Folder 18)
  - Student Academics--Independent Study (Box 43, Folder 19)
  - Student Academics--Laboratories (Box 43, Folder 20)
  - Student Academics--Laboratories--, 1890's--1918 (Box 43, Folder 21)
  - Student Academics--Laboratories--, Early 1960's (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - Student Academics--Laboratories--Biology (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - Student Academics--Libraries (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - Student Academics--Misc. (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - Student Academics--Misc., 1950's (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - Student Activities--Rallies--Parades (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Student Activities--Rallies--Parades--UC Fence (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Student Amusements--Fol.1 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Student Amusements--Fol.2 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Student Amusements--Fol.3 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Student Amusements--Fol.4 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Student Amusements--Fol.5 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Student Amusements--Fol.6 (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Student Amusements-- Early Years, (1819-1918)-- (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Student Automobiles (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Student Dances (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Student Demonstrations (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Student Demonstrations--April Third Movement--AEL--Applied Electronics Lab (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Student Demonstrations--April Third Movement--Encina;Trustees Meet Students (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Student Demonstrations--April Third Movement-- SRI, 1969-- (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Student Demonstrations--Black Student Union (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Student Demonstrations--Bookstore (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Student Demonstrations--Computation Center (Box 45, Folder 18)
  - Student Demonstrations--Franklin, H. Bruce--Dismissal--Fol.1 (Box 45, Folder 19)
  - Student Demonstrations--Franklin, H. Bruce--Dismissal--Fol.2 (Box 45, Folder 20)
  - Student Demonstrations--Free Campus Movement (Box 45, Folder 21)
  - Student Demonstrations--Lodge, Henry Cabot--Speech Disruption (Box 45, Folder 22)
  - Student Demonstrations--Medical Center (Box 45, Folder 23)
  - Student Demonstrations--Old Union Sit-in (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Student Demonstrations--Strike-- Fol.1, 1970-- (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Student Demonstrations--Strike-- Fol.2, 1970-- (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Student Demonstrations--Strike-- Fol.3, 1970-- (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Student Demonstrations--Strike-- Fol.4, 1970-- (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Student Demonstrations--Strike-- Fol.5, 1970-- (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Student Demonstrations--Strike-- Fol.6, 1970-- (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Student Demonstrations--Strike-- Fol.7, 1970-- (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Student Demonstrations--Strike-- Fol.8, 1970-- (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - Student Demonstrations--Strike-- Fol.9, 1970-- (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Student Demonstrations--Students for a Democratic Society (SDS) (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Student Demonstrations--Vietnam Moratorium (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Student Groups--Fol.1 (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - Student Groups--Fol.2 (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Student Groups--Fol.3 (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Student Groups--Fol.4 (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Student Groups--Fol.5 (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - Student Groups--Fol.6 (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - Student Groups--Faculty with Students (Box 46, Folder 19)
  - Student Groups--Fraternities (Box 46, Folder 20)
  - Student Groups--Fraternities--Dedication of Fraternity Cluster (Box 46, Folder 21)
  - Student Groups--Sororities (Box 46, Folder 22)
  - Student Housing--Aerial Views (Box 46, Folder 23)
  - Student Housing--Branner Hall (Box 46, Folder 24)
  - Student Housing--Crothers and Crothers Memorial Halls (Box 46, Folder 25)
  - Student Housing--Encina Commons (Box 46, Folder 26)
  - Student Housing--Encina Hall--Exteriors--Fol.1 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Student Housing--Encina Hall--Exteriors--Fol.2 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Student Housing--Encina Hall--Exteriors--Fol.3 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Student Housing--Encina Hall--Exteriors--Fol.4 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Student Housing--Encina Hall--Interiors (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Student Housing--Encina Hall Residents--Fol.1 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Student Housing--Encina Hall Residents--Fol.2 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Student Housing--Encina Hall Residents--Group Portraits--Fol.1 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Student Housing--Encina Hall Residents--Group Portraits--Fol.2 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Student Housing--Encina Hall Residents--Group Portraits--Fol.3 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Student Housing--Escondido Village (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Student Housing--Florence Moore Hall (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Student Housing--Fraternities--Interior (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Student Housing--Fraternities and Sororities--Exteriors Fol.1 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Student Housing--Fraternities and Sororities--Exteriors Fol.2 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Student Housing--Fraternities and Sororities--Exteriors Fol.3 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Student Housing--Fraternities and Sororities--Exteriors Fol.4 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Student Housing--Lagunita Court (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Student Housing--Manzanita Park (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Student Housing--Roble Hall I--Fol.1 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Student Housing--Roble Hall I--Fol.2 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Student Housing--Roble Hall I--Fol.3 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Student Housing--Roble Hall I--Residents (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Student Housing--Roble Hall II (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Student Housing--Sequoia Hall (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Student Housing--Stern Hall (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Student Housing--Student Rooms--Men--Fol.1 (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Student Housing--Student Rooms--Men--Fol.2 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Student Housing--Student Rooms--Women (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Student Housing--Toyon Hall--Exteriors (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Student Housing--Toyon Hall--Interiors (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Student Housing--Wilbur Hall--Exteriors (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Student Housing--Wilbur Hall--Interiors (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - Student Life-- Fol.1, 1892-1902-- (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Student Life-- Fol.2, 1892-1902-- (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Student Life-- Fol.1, 1902-1920-- (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Student Life-- Fol.2, 1902-1920-- (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Student Life-- Fol.3, 1902-1920-- (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Student Life-- Fol.1, c.1920-- (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Student Life-- Fol.2, 1920's-1930's-- (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Student Life--, 1930's-1940's (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Student Life-- Roger White photos, 1930's-1940's-- (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Student Life--, 1940's (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Student Life--, 1950's (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Student Life--, Early 1960's (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Student Life--, Mid-1960's (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - Student Life-- Misc., 1960's-- (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Student Life-- PACE Photos by Jones/Ansel Adams--Fol.1, 1960's-- (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - Student Life-- PACE Photos by Jones/Ansel Adams--Fol.2, 1960's-- (Box 51, Folder 16)
  - Student Life-- PACE Photos by Jones/Ansel Adams--Fol.3, 1960's-- (Box 51, Folder 17)
  - Student Life-- PACE Photos by Jones/Ansel Adams--Fol.4, 1960's-- (Box 51, Folder 18)
  - Student Life-- PACE Photos by Jones/Ansel Adams--Fol.5, 1960's-- (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Student Life-- PACE Photos by Jones/Ansel Adams--Fol.6, 1960's-- (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Student Life-- Misc.--Fol.1, 1970's-- (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Student Life-- Misc.--Fol.2, 1970's-- (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Student Life-- Freshman Orientation, 1980's-1982-- (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Student Life--Epidemics, (1918) (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Student Life--Faculty-Senior Baseball--Fol.1 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Student Life--Facultu-Senior Baseball--Fol.2 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Student Life--Faculty-Senior Baseball--Fol.3 (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Student Life--Faculty-Senior Baseball--Fol.4 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Student Life--Faculty-Senior Baseball--Fol.5 (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Student Life--Faculty-Senior Baseball--Fol.6 (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Student Life--Faculty-Senior Baseball--Fol.7 (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - Student Life--Faculty-Senior Baseball--Fol.8 (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - Student Life--Foreign Students (Box 52, Folder 15)
  - Student Officers--ASSU (Box 52, Folder 16)
  - Students for a Democratic Society (SDS) (Box 52, Folder 17)
  - Students--Individual--(By Name)--Classes 1918-1923--Hester Proctor Collection (Box 52, Folder 18)
  - Students--Individual--Will Irwin Collection--Fol.1 (Box 52, Folder 19)
  - Students--Individual--Will Irwin Collection--Fol.2 (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Students--Miscellaneous (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Students--Quad Poses, (c. 1891-1902) (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Students--Quad Poses, (c.1902-1920) (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Students--Quad Poses, 1920's (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Students--Quad Poses--, 1930'3 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Students--Quad Poses--, 1940's (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Students--Quad Poses--, 1950's (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Students--Quad Poses--, 1960's (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Students--Quad Poses--, 1970's (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Studio Watts Drama Group (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - Study of Education at Stanford (Box 53, Folder 12)
  - Summer Festival of the Arts (Box 53, Folder 13)
  - Swords and Sandals (Box 53, Folder 14)
  - Telegraph Office (Box 53, Folder 15)
  - Television in Classrooms (Box 53, Folder 16)
  - Terman Engineering Awards--Terman Scholastic Awards (Box 53, Folder 17)
  - Transportation on Campus (Box 53, Folder 18)
  - Tresidder Memorial Union (Box 53, Folder 19)
  - Trophies (Box 53, Folder 20)
  - Trustees--Group Pictures (Box 53, Folder 21)
  - United Nations Members--Visits to Stanford (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - University of California (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - University Press (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Varian Physics Laboratory (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Water Carnival (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Well, Campus (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - White Memorial Plaza (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Women's Army Corps (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Women's Club House (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Women's Liberation Party (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Women's Suffrage (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - World War I (1917-1918)--Military on campus (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - Y.M.C.A. (Box 54, Folder 14)
  - Y.M.C.A. (Box 54, Folder 15)
  - Youth Opportunity Program, (1970s) (Box 54, Folder 16)
  - Zoology Club (Box 54, Folder 17)
- Stanford Family Photographs, Series 2
  Photographs of family members and friends, Stanford residences, the Palo Alto Stock Farm, and the Central Pacific Railroad.
  - Hewes, David--Fol. 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Hewes, David--Fol. 2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lathrop, Anna Maria (Mrs. David Hewes)--Fol. 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Lathrop, Anna Maria (Mrs. David Hewes)--Fol. 2 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lathrop, Ariel (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Lathrop, Charles G. (and Mrs.) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Lathrop, Daniel S. (and Family) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Lathrop, Dyer (and Family) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Lathrop Family (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Lathrop, Henry C. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Lathrop, Leland Stanford (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Stanford, Alice Herrick--Fol.1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Stanford, Alice Herrick--Fol.2 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Stanford, Charles (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Stanford, Helen M. (and Relatives) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Stanford Family--Fol.1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Stanford Family--Fol.2 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Stanford Family--Statuary (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Stanford Family Statue--Fol.1 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Stanford Family Statue--Fol.2 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Stanford Friends--Fol.1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Friends--Fol.2 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Stanford, Jane L.--Fol.1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Stanford, Jane L.--Fol.2 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Stanford, Jane L.--Fol.3 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Stanford, Jane L.--Dress (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Stanford, Jane L.--Father Serra Monument--Fol.1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Stanford, Jane L.--Father Serra Monument--Fol.2 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Stanford, Jane L.--Father Serra Monument--Fol.3 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Stanford, Jane L.--Father Serra Monument--Fol.4 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Stanford, Jane L.--Funeral (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Stanford, Jane L.--Kindergartens (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Stanford, Jane L.--Travels (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Stanford, Jane L. with Leland, Jr. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Stanford, Josiah Sr. (father of Leland Stanford) (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Stanford, Josiah (brother of Leland Stanford) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Stanford, Josiah W.--Fol.1 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Stanford, Josiah W.--Fol.2 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Stanford, Josiah W.--Fol.3 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Stanford/Lathrop--unidentified (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Stanford, Leland--funeral (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Stanford, Leland--Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Stanford, Leland--Portraits--Fol.1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Stanford, Leland--Portraits--Fol.2 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Stanford, Leland--Rutherford B. Hayes and Benjamin Harrison Visits (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Stanford, Leland Jr.--Drawings (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Stanford, Leland Jr.--Memorial Tablet (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Stanford, Leland Jr.--Portraits (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Stanford, Leland Jr.--Toys and museum objects--Fol.1 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Stanford, Leland Jr.--Toys and museum objects--Fol.2 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Stanford, Leland Jr.--Toys and museum objects--Fol.3. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Stanford, Thomas Welton (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Taylor, Agnes Stanford (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Taylor, Edward Robeson (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Stanford Residences--Albany (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Stanford Residences--Cold Springs/Michigan Bluff (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Stanford Residences--Palo Alto--Before Alteration (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Stanford Residences--Palo Alto--Earthquake (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Stanford Residences--Palo Alto--Exterior--Front/Side View--Fol.1 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Stanford Residences--Palo Alto--Exterior--Front/Side View--Fol.2 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Stanford Residences--Palo Alto--Exterior--Rear View (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Stanford Residences--Palo Alto--Grounds--Fol.1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Stanford Residences--Palo Alto--Grounds--Fol.2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Stanford Residences--Palo Alto--Interior (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Stanford Residences--Palo Alto--Remodeling (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Stanford Residences--Sacramento--Fol.1 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Stanford Residences--Sacramento--Fol.2 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Stanford Residences--Sacramento--Fol.3 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Stanford Residences--Sacramento--Historical American--Building Survey (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Stanford Residences--Sacramento--Muybridge--Fol.1 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Stanford Residences--Sacramento--Muybridge--Fol.2 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Stanford Residences--Sacramento--Muybridge--Fol.3 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Stanford Residences--Sacramento--Muybridge--Fol.4 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Stanford Residences--San Francisco--Exterior--Fol.1 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Stanford Residences--San Francisco--Interior--Fol.2 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Stanford Residences--San Francisco--Interior (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Stanford Residences--Washington D.C. (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Stock Farm--Buildings (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Stock Farm--Buildings--Barns and Stables--Fol.1 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Stock Farm--Buildings--Barns and Stables--Fol.2 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Stock Farm--Buildings--Barns and Stables--Fol.3 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Stock Farm--Buildings--Panoramas--Fol.1 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Stock Farm--Buildings--Panoramas--Fol.2 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Stock Farm--Employees (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Stock Farm--Grounds (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Stock Farm--Grounds--Governor's Avenue--Fol.1 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Stock Farm--Grounds--Governor's Avenue--Fol.2 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Stock Farm--Grounds--Lake Lagunita (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Stock Farm--Grounds--Treat collection Fol.1, (1886)-- (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Stock Farm--Grounds--Treat collection Fol.2, (1886)-- (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Stock Farm--Grounds--Treat collection Fol.3, (1886)-- (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Stock Farm--Grounds--Treat collection Lake Lagunita, (1886)-- (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Stock Farm--Horses--Fol.1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Stock Farm--Horses--Fol.2 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Stock Farm--Horses--Fol.3 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Stock Farm--Horses--Fol.4 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Stock Farm--Horses--Occident (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Stock Farm--Monuments (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Stock Farm--Tracks (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Vina Ranch--Fol.1 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Vina Ranch--Fol.2 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Warm Springs Ranch--Fol.1 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Warm Springs Ranch--Fol.2 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Warm Springs Ranch--Fol.3 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Warm Springs Ranch--Fol.4 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Warm Springs Ranch--Vineyards and Winery (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Warm Springs--Town and hotel (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Central Pacific--Gold Spike and Memorabilia--Fol.1 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Photograph of the Gold Spike., 1968 Dec.
    - Photograph of the Gold Spike
    - Photograph of the Gold Spike, 1968 Dec. 3
  - Central Pacific--Gold Spike and Memorabilia--Fol.2 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Photograph, front side, of Gold Spike, shovel, sledge hammer, and other memorabilia related to the completion of the Central Pacific, 1948 Sept.; recto
    - Back side of photograph showing property stamps of previous owners of the photograph, 1948 Sept.; verso
    - Photograph of a gold spike and other memorabilia., recto
    - Reverse side of photograph of the Gold Spike., verso
      Caption Reads: From the casting of "The Last Spike," a surplus nugget, was taken, from which were made finger rings and charms for the Stanford family as this photograph shows.
    - A silver spike used in Central Pacific Railroad line., 1971 Dec. 12
  - Central Pacific--Gold Spike Ceremony (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Photograph of four men who contributed to the creation of the Central Pacific Railroad line., recto
    - Reverse of Gold Spike Ceremony photograph. The reverse describes the four men in the picture., verso
    - Photograph of men and women at the Union Pacific and the Central Pacific in Promontory, Utah. General Dodge is also in the crowd., 1869 May, 10
      At the joining of the tracks of the Union Pacific, May 10, 1869, Promontory, Utah, General Dodge fifth to the right of the tracks
    - Men and women at Gold Spike Ceremony in Promontory, Utah., 1869 May 10
  - Central Pacific--Governor Stanford Locomotive (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Governor Stanford's locomotive, recto
    - Reverse of photograph of Governor Stanford's locomotive in field of old Roble Hall (later Sequoia) before removed to Stanford Museum., verso
    - A photograph of Governor Stanford Locomotive being moved into the Stanford Museum., 1916
  - Central Pacific--Governor Stanford Locomotive--Color (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Central Pacific--Hart Album--Fol.1 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Governor Stanford's private car in Sacramento rail yard., 1975 Apr.
    - The "Car Stanford" private car presented to Mr. Stanford by Mrs. Stanford., 1882 Oct.
      Caption Reads: Car Stanford; Built At C.P.R. Car Works, Sacratmento, Cal.
  - Central Pacific--Hart Album--Fol.2 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Reverse of photo taken at Monument Point, a short distance from Promontory and depicts the change made in transportation from the covered wagon to the iron horse., 1869 May; verso
    - Photo of special trains of the Central Pacific and the Union Pacific after the "last spike" ceremony., 1869; recto
    - Reverse of the photo depicting the Central Pacific special which took Leland Stanford and party to the "last spike" ceremony with locomotive "Jupiter"., 1869; verso
    - Photo of Governor Stanford's special train at Monument Point, Utah on May 10, 1869, the day the last spike was driven in the first transconitinental., 1869 May 10; recto
    - Reverse of photo of Governor Stanford's special train at Monument Point, Utah on May 10, 1869, the day the last spike was driven in the first transconitinental., 1869 May 10; verso
    - Photograph taken at the Gold Spike ceremony in Promontory, Utah. The people are attempting to fix the wire., 1869 May 10
      Caption Reads: "Fixing the Wire"
    - Photo of the Gold Spike ceremony at Promontory, Utah. Leland Stanford holding sledge hammer at center., 1869 May 10; recto
      Caption Reads: The Last Rail is Laid. Scene at Promontory, May 10, 1869.
    - Reverse of photo depicting Leland Stanford holding sledge hammer at center - Gold Spike Ceremony, Promontory, Utah, May 10, 1869., 1869 May 10; verso
    - Photo taken from the Union Pacific locomotive #119, looking westward, and shows the four companies of the 21st Infantry in formation alongside the track. Central Pacific's locomotive "Jupiter" and tent-building of Promontory are also shown., 1869 May 10; recto
    - Reverse of photo taken from the Union Pacific locomotive #119, looking westward, and shows the four companies of the 21st Infantry in formation alongside the track. Central Pacific's locomotive "Jupiter" and tent-building of Promontory are also shown., 1869 May 10; verso
  - Central Pacific--Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Photograph of men working on the Central Pacific railroad.
      "Bending Iron"
    - Photograph of a water boy for one of the gangs of Chinese laborers who played an important part in contruction of what is now the Overland Route of the Southern Pacific eastward over the High Sierra of California and across Nevada and Utah., recto
    - Reverse of photograph of a water boy for one of the gangs of Chinese laborers who played an important part in contruction of what is now the Overland Route of the Southern Pacific eastward over the High Sierra of California and across Nevada and Utah., verso
    - Photograph of the Central Pacific railroad.
    - Photograph shows the engine of the "Leland Stanford" locomotive as it appeared when first plaice in service., 1863 Nov. 11; recto
      Caption Reads: 1. Locomotive "Gov. Stanford,"
    - Reverse of photograph which shows the engine of the "Leland Stanford" locomotive as it appeared when first plaice in service., 1863 Nov. 11; verso
    - Photograph of a locomotive of trestle, near American River.
      Caption Reads: 135. Locomotive on Trestle, near American River.
    - Photograph of a locomotive near Deeth with Mount Halleck in the distance.
      Caption Reads: 349 Scene near Deeth. Mount Halleck in distance.
    - Photograph of a locomotive traveling through a newly dug hill.
  - Central Pacific--Officers (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Photograph: Top row lt. to rt. Mark Hopkins, E.B. Crocker, B.B. Redding?, E.H. Miller?; Bottom Row lt. to rt. S.S.Montague, Charles Crocka, Leland Stanford, C.P. Huntington
    - Photograph of the eight men who contributed to the construction of the Central Pacific Rail Road.
      Caption Reads: Officers of the Central Pacific Rail Road
  - Central Pacific--Private Car (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Photograph of the Leland Stanford Locomotive., recto
      Caption Reads: Built in 1868 by Union Iron Works. Run in Market St. from Sausous to 17th and Valencia. After used as Stanford's private car. Used afterwards as fray-car. Later wold to the Gobart Mills, Trucfsee.
    - Photograph of an open-air observation car at "Cape Horn" in the Sierra Nevada mountains of California. It was at this point in the mountains that passengers were given the opportunity to view the deep American River Canyon., 1870s; recto
    - Reverse of the photograph of an open-air observation car at "Cape Horn" in the Sierra Nevada mountains of California. It was at this point in the mountains that passengers were given the opportunity to view the deep American River Canyon., 1870s; verso
    - Picture depicting the Central Pacific railroad traveling through a town., 1971 Dec.